

Bahadir Omer Cakmak

Nationality: Turkish

\((+48) 517220852

Date of birth: 27/08/1999

Gender: Male

™ Email address: bahadir0646@gmail.com

Website: https://cakmak.netlify.app

9 GitHub: : https://github.com/bomercakmak

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bahadir-omer-cakmak-4b4036204

ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer with more than 3 years of experience. Since the beginning of my programming journey, I have been focusing on expanding my knowledge and abilities in software development, programming and quality assurance with a special emphasis in web technologies. I frequently use popular web technologies including, but not limited to, **HTML5**, **CSS**, **Bootstrap**, **JavaScript**, **PHP**, **Node.js**, **React**, **Redux**, **Next.js**, **Firebase**. By various internships that I have made, I am always trying to excel my communication and organizational abilities with resourceful approach to solving diverse problems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer Intern

BCS-IT GmbH [01/06/2021 - 01/10/2021]

Location: Langenfeld, Germany

- SaleVali Integrated Multi-Channel E-Commerce Web application.
- Successfully generated front-end programming utilizing HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React,
 Redux-Saga, Formik, npm, and various other third-party libraries.
- Designed and implemented back-end system using a variety of programming languages and web technologies including: **Node.js**, **PHP**, **Loopback**, **MongoDB**, **RESTful API**.
- Integrated several software to the development process using **Agile** methodology (**Scrum**): **Git, Gitflo w, Bitbucket,** and **Jira**.
- Attended daily **Scrum** meetings, **Sprint planning and reviews**, communicated with other developers and managers, come up with creative solutions.
- Developed, maintained, and tested React-based complex and large web applications.

Supervisor Feedback: Omer was a successful, all-round trainee that made significant contributions to his projects. He has featly completed the required assignments on a timely manner, and helped the team to carry the project to the next level. Having demonstrated the required skills to get promoted to a Full Stack Web Developer position, he was meticulous and determined to accomplish his goals. It was a great pleasure for me and the other team members to work with him. I would recommend Omer to every passionate team that is looking towards a fresh web developer with extensive experience.

Software Engineer Intern

Mibgate GmbH [01/07/2020 - 01/10/2020]

Location: Düsseldorf, Germany

- Used development tools HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, TypeScript, and
- **Node.js** on regular basis.
- Supported software engineering projects in **Agile** work environment
- Handled scripting tasks for debugging and automation using **Cypress**.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.
- Partnered with company mentor to learn **best practices** in software design.

Supervisor Feedback: Our intern Bahadır Omer Cakmak worked based on Web development. He used recent and industry wide technologies that are popularly used in the software engineering and web development community thoroughly. He has expanded his programming skills by working hard daily on real life programming challenges. He has given various speeches at the daily meeting, which has improved his public speaking and communication skills.

Software Engineer Intern

AnyWork GmbH [01/07/2019 - 01/10/2019]

Location: Düsseldorf, Germany

- Created interactive websites with software development department using **JavaScript** and **React**
- framework.
- Worked alongside product managers to re-architect a multi-page web app into a single page webapp
- built in **React**.
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web
- functionality and speed.

Supervisor Feedback: The trainee can achieve to applications development, projects and website development. Trainer can work as a part of a team with cooperation. Trainee can be able to work with JavaScript and React on Front-end Development. Monitoring international activities and working as a team member to software development and project development.

Social Media Manager

Heremood GmbH [08/2018 – 06/2019]

Location: Cologne, Germany

- Designed and executed global social media selling strategy across 125,000 followers on Store's Website, Amazon, Ebay, Etsy, Instagram, and Facebook.
- Regularly used technologies to sell product on store website; Wordpress, Shopify, BigCommerce,
 Google Analytics, Google Ads and GoDaddy.
- Technologies used regularly to create social media posts, videos and blogs: **Adobe Photoshop**, **Adobe Premiere Pro**, **Final Cut Pro**, **DaVinci Resolve**, **Microsoft Office 365** and **Canva**.
- Provided digital marketing solutions to Amazon FBA / FBM businesses

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Vistula University [01/09/2018 - 01/03/2022]

- Professional specialization on Web Technologies Engineering.
- Member of Computer Engineering Club.
- **Mentor** in the university's mentoring program.

English Language Preparatory Program

Cankaya University [01/09/2017 - 01/06/2018]

High School Diploma

Acı High School

PROJECTS

SaleVali

[06/2021 - 10/2021]

SaleVali is **React-based** web application that aims to integrate various E-Commerce and Shipping platforms, in a single page web application. The main goal of the application is to have a single, user-friendly environment for online-retailers, resolving the hassle and complexity of selling products, managing invoice, checking stocks, and tracking customers, in a variety of platforms.

Ahsen

[09/2020 - 06/2021]

Ahsen is an **Order Management System (OMS)** for wholesaler. An order management system (OMS) is a digital way to manage the lifecycle of an order. It tracks all the information and processes, including order entry, inventory management, fulfillment and after-sales service. An OMS offers visibility to both the business and the buyer. Organizations can have near real-time insight into inventories and customers can check when an order will arrive.

COVID-19 Tracker

[05/2020 - 06/2020]

This project created for to draw attention to COVID-19 and make the world better and healthier.

• I have many more projects. You can access my projects on my <u>Personal Website</u> or <u>GitHub account</u>.

SKILLS

Software Engineering & Full Stack Web Development

HTML - CSS - Sass - Responsive Design - Bootstrap - JavaScript - PHP - Python - TypeScript - npm - Node.js - React - Next.js - Redux - React Router - Material-UI - Express.js - Asynchronous Programming - Firebase - MongoDB - MySQL - Git - Gitflow Workflow - GitHub - Bitbucket - Agile - Scrum - Jira

Social Media & E-Commerce

Microsoft Office 365 - Wordpress - Shopify - BigCommerce - Google Ads - Adobe Photoshop - Adobe Premiere Pro - Final Cut Pro - DaVinci Resolve - Canva

Soft Skills

Problem Solving - Critical Thinking - Communication - Teamwork - Creativity - Time Management - Visual Thinking - Work Ethics - Adaptability

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s):

Turkish

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1
SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

Azerbaijani

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1
SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

German

LISTENING A1 READING A1 WRITING A1
SPOKEN INTERACTION A1

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

JunctionX Budapest Hackathon 2019

[Budapest, Hungary]

https://www.hackathon.com/event/junctionx-budapest-2019-5d35791d2e538f001c438cbe

Google Digital Marketing 2019

[Ankara, Turkey]

Hack Yeah Hackathon Warsaw 2018

[Warsaw, Poland] https://hackyeah.pl/

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Table Tennis

I played professional table tennis for 2 years. I have 1 city championship in table tennis. I'm just playing as a hobby right now.

Hiking

As a software engineer, we can stay still for a long time because we spend so much time on the computer. Therefore, it is a very good hobby to Hiking regularly

VOLUNTEERING

Volunteer to Plant Trees

Life couldn't exist without trees. Currently, the world faces the challenges of climate change and wildlife preservation, along with having to support billions of people. We need solutions. And trees could hold the answer.